## Morteza Shoushtari

Graduate Research Assistant

✓ shoushtari.morteza@live.com

 $\Box$  +1 (408) 752-1087

www.mshoushtari.com

in linkedin.com/in/morteza-shoushtari

#### Summary

I am a Ph.D. candidate in the department of Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE), at Brigham Young University. Currently, I am working on physical layer security, and secure error-correction coding. I received an M.Sc. degree in Information Technology from Shiraz University, Iran, in 2013, and I have around 6 years of work experience as an IT administrator and network engineer in companies such as Huawei Technologies Co. and JYAN Construction Co.

#### Interests

- Wire/Wireless Networks
- Cloud Computing
- Cryptography and Physical Layer Security

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D., Computer Engineering

Dissertation topic: Secure Error-Correction Coding

Brigham Young University, Utah, USA

• Years: 2019 - 2023 (expected)

• GPA: 3.74/4

M.Sc., Information Technology (IT) Shiraz University, Shiraz, IRAN

• Years: 2011 - 2013

B.Sc., Computer Engineering

Sadjad University of Technology, Mashhad, IRAN

• Years: 2006 - 2010

# SELECTED PUBLICATION

- Morteza Shoushtari, Farah Arabian and Willie Harrison, "From Privacy Protection to Analyzing Users' Behavior: The Crucial Role of Information Theory in the Metaverse" under review in Proc. IEEE Intermountain Engineering, Technology, and Computing Conference (i-ETC), 2023.
- Morteza Shoushtari and Willie Harrison, "Optimizing Finite Blocklength Nested Linear Codes: Using the Worst Code to Find the Best Code", under review in Proc. IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory (ISIT), 2023.
- Morteza Shoushtari, Farah Arabian and Willie Harrison, "Post-Quantum Cryptography Based on Codes: A Game Changer for Secrecy in Aeronautical Mobile Telemetry" in Proc. of the International Telemetry Conference (ITC), Las Vegas, NV, US, Oct. 2022.
- Morteza Shoushtari and Willie Harrison, "Secrecy coding in the Integrated Network Enhanced Telemetry (iNET)" in Proc. of the International Telemetry Conference (ITC), Las Vegas, NV, US, Oct. 2021.
- Morteza Shoushtari and Willie Harrison, "New Dual Relationships for Error-Correcting Wiretap Codes" in Proc. of IEEE Information Theory Workshop (ITW), Kanazawa, Japan, Oct. 2021.
- Willie Harrison and Morteza Shoushtari, "On Caching with Finite Blocklength Coding for Secrecy over the Binary Erasure Wiretap Channel" in Proc. of IEEE Wireless Telecommunications Symposium (WTS), San Francisco, US, Apr. 2021.

Work EXPERIENCES

### Brigham Young University, UTAH, USA Graduate Research Assistant

Jan 2019 - present

• RA with the emphasize on physical layer security and secrecy/error-correction codes

## IT Dep. HUAWEI Company, Tehran, Iran

Aug 2016 - Aug 2017

#### IT Administrator

- Maintained communication networks, monitor network performance, and resolving any technical issues
- Provided 24\*7 level-one support to over 850 clients
- Installed and configured network devices, including routers, switches, wireless AP's, cameras, and video conferences

## IT Dep. JYAN Company, Tehran, Iran

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

#### **Network Engineer**

- Maintained communication networks, monitored network performance, and resolved any technical issues
- Provided 24\*7 level-one support over 180 clients
- Installed and configured network devices, including routers, switches, wireless AP's, camera's, and video conferences

# IT Dep. Persia Cloud Company, Tehran, Iran

Jun 2015 - Jan 2016

#### **Network Engineer**

- Installed and configured 2X and IIRAS cloud platforms (IIAS, PAAS)
- Installed and configured Microsoft Servers (CRM, SharePoint, Lync)

# IT Dep. LOTUS Company, Tehran, Iran

Nov 2013 - Jun 2015

#### Website Developer

• Programmed and maintained company's website (lotuslaptop.com)

#### IT Dep. KARMA Engineering Company, Iran Technical Support

Nov 2011 - Nov 2013

- Maintained communication networks and resolved any technical issues
- Provided 24\*7 level-one support to over 50 clients

#### Members and Honors

- Best paper award, International Telemetry Conference, 2022.
- Second best graduate student paper award, International Telemetry Conference, 2021.
- Member of IEEE Communication Society (ComSoc).
- Member of IEEE Information Theory Society (ITSoc).
- Outstanding IT engineer in Huawei Technologies Company, 2017.
- Monthly star engineer in JYANE Company, 2016.

#### CERTIFICATES AND SKILLS

- Network Certificates:
  - o CompTIA A+ and Network+
  - o CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate)
  - o MCITP (Microsoft Certified IT Professional)
  - o HCNA (Huawei Certified Network Associate)
- Familiar with:
  - o Configuration of network devices, such as switches, routers o Network troubleshooting
  - o Cloud Computing Architecture such as AWS, 2x (Parallels)
  - o C++/Python/Matlab programming